喂，Alex！你今晚跟我们去酒馆不
Oi, Alex! You coming with us to the pub tonight?
当然了，哥们，不过这回得换个人送Henry回家
Yeah, of course, man. But someone else is driving Henry home this time.
哦，得了吧，不就吐了那么一丢丢嘛
Oh, come off it. It was only a wee bit of vomit.
呵，行吧，我可以带……带……呃……Kyle
Heh, alright then. I can take... take... uh... Kyle.
啥情况？他去哪了……呃……呃……呃……Sebastian
What's happening? Where did he uh... uh... uh... Sebastian!
Alex，我感觉不太对劲，呃……
Alex, I'm not feeling so good. Uh...
哇哦！我嘴里好像溅进来一点
Whoa! I think I got a little in my mouth there.
这就是传送的毛病
That's the thing with teleporting, though.
有时候吧，你懂的，会有人正好站在那
Sometimes a person is, you know, standing there.
你杀了他！你把Henry给炸了！
You killed him! You exploded Henry!
哇哦，嘿，别叫他名字，不然该有感情了
Whoa, hey, don't give it a name. You'll get attached.
那可是个大活人！
It was a person!
而且他那些上好的器官，这会儿正在柏油路上被煎得滋滋作响呢
And it has perfectly good organs, getting a light seer on the asphalt right now.
所以你要是能别大惊小怪了，然后去拿个冷藏箱过来，那就再好不过了
So if you could quit your fuss and then fetch a cooler, that'd be great.
我猜把我其他朋友搞不见的也是你吧？
And I assume it was you who gommaged my other friends?
是啊，我不小心把我的传送小玩意儿调成了“创伤性瞬间雾化”模式
Yeah, I accidentally had my tele-gizmo set to traumatic spontaneous atomization
而不是“传送”
instead of teleport.
这破玩意儿真难搞
Dang thing's so fidgety.
你来这干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我才想问你呢，小傻瓜
I was gonna ask you the same thing, silly.
一个人跑到地球另一端，除了身上穿的衣服、脚上蹬的鞋
Running off halfway across the globe with nothing but the clothes on your back and the shoes on your feet
还有你脑子里的GPS芯片，啥也没带
and the GPS chip in your brain.
就好像你想躲着我似的
It's almost like you're trying to hide from me or something.
不，当然没有
No, of course not.
我只是想早点到位，准备上下节课
I just thought I'd get in place early for the next lesson.
好孩子
Good boy.
英格兰这片土地选得太对了，我的小伙子
The land of England was a perfect choice, my lad,
因为你很难找到一个比这更标志性的地方去……
as you'd be hard-pressed to find a more iconic state to
又唱又跳，说着骚话，戴着叮当响的铃铛
prance and sing, making jokes to bling whilst wearing bells that ring.
呃，啥玩意儿？
Uh, what?
哦我亲爱的孩子，我指的当然是那神出鬼没的宫廷小丑
Oh dear boy, but of course it is the elusive court jester to whom I refer.
这个标志性的傻憨憨，以其机智和搞怪闻名于各大王室宫廷
The iconic silly goose, famous for gracing royal courts with wit and whimsy.
那么现在就让我们穿越时空，揭开这个高雅职业的神秘面纱
So let us now travel back in time to unwind a profession sublime
学习关于这个最精致的搞笑角色的所有秘密
and learn everything behind the jokester role most refined.
哦不要啊
Oh no.
没错，Alex
That's right, Alex.
今天，我就来教你如何当一名宫廷小丑并活下来
Today, I'm going to teach you how to survive as a court jester.
我非得穿这个吗？
Do I have to wear this?
这是啥？
What is this?
你可能觉得吧，宫廷小丑这种傻乎乎的玩意儿，是个非常欧洲特色的现象
The silly court jester, you may believe, a phenomenon very Europe-y.
他们为统治者和暴君卖力地跳舞，吟诵着异想天开的俏皮话
For rulers and tyrants, they dance with flair, a whimsically witty soliloquy.
但说实话，傻瓜哪儿都有
But truth be told, the fool was everywhere.
从中国到玛雅，一点都不抢手
From China to Maya, they're far from rare.
他们的名字可能不同，但讲的笑话都差不多
Their name may change, but matching jokes they zing.
一个英国傻瓜在罗马也能这辈子全都有
An English fool in Rome would fit in square.
这整个视频都要这样吗
Is this gonna be the whole video?
全世界每一个国王身边，少不了一个小丑挤眉弄眼
Across the world, for each and every king. A prancing gesture, twas a common thing.
他们的存在夺目光彩，没人会觉得奇怪，因为大家都知道傻瓜能带来愉快
Their presence in splendor, none bat an eye. As all knew well, the merriment fools bring.
让我们先去欧洲宫廷一瞧，他们的报酬可一点都不少
To European courts, let us first spy. Their services paid with nothing too shy.
成片的土地和堆成山的钞票
Acres of land and golden coin to buy.
所以你就翘起二郎腿放轻松，顺便祈祷自己别被征兵吧
So kick back and relax, and hope you don't get drafted.
啥？
What?
就像生活中所有美好的事物一样
Like all good things in life,
任何想法在被人尝试武器化之前，都算不上真正的有价值
no idea is truly worth their salt until someone tries to weaponize it.
而备受喜爱的宫廷小丑，终日在世界各地的王室宫廷里蹦跶，自然也不例外
And the beloved jester, ever prancing about the royal courts of the world, was no exception.
既然他们能在晾衣绳上跳舞，为啥不能去前线蹦跶呢
So if they can dance around on a clothesline, why not the front line?
没错，虽然你朝九晚五的工作听起来可能有点古怪有趣
That's right, while your 9 to 5 might sound like some wacky fun,
在你作为宫廷小丑的新生活中……
and your new life as a court jester,
你很可能会发现自己被强制加班，骑马冲在军队的最前线
you may very well find yourself with some mandatory overtime riding in the vanguard of armies.
因为讲故事和玩杂耍是门艺术，挑衅引战也是
For while telling tales and juggling flails is an art, so too is rage baiting.
从欧洲到日本的小丑，都可以被用作一种心理战术
And jesters from Europe to Japan could be used as a form of psychological warfare.
不过这跟你关系不大，除非……呃……
But this isn't really relevant to you, unless, uh...
哦嘿你看，黑斯廷斯战役
Oh hey look, the Battle of Hastings.
我的天，我们在这儿安全吗
Oh my god, are we safe here?
哈哈，当然不安全
Haha, No.
我不想死在这儿
I don't want to die here.
我也不想，伙计
Me neither, champ.
大多数小丑也不想
And most jesters didn't either.
所以他们才尽力通过讲笑话和带来一些轻松气氛来鼓舞士气
That's why they did their best to boost troop morale by telling jokes and bringing some levity.
所以你为啥不试试那个，而不是在这儿抱怨呢
So how about you try that instead of bitching?
我……嗯……你管会飞的猴子叫什么
I, um, what do you call a monkey that flies?
猴子是啥
What's a monkey?
热气球狒狒
A hot air baboon.
你以为是啥，中世纪气球吗
You thought what, mid balloons?
我觉得他说的三个词儿里有俩他都没听过，不过这笑话再过几个世纪肯定能火
I don't think he's heard of three of those things, but that would have killed in a few centuries,
精神可嘉啊，Alex
so, A for effort, Alex.
那现在咋办？
Well, what now?
小丑除了擅长鼓舞士气，还能通过嘲讽敌方前线来打击敌人
While great at boosting morale, a jester also served to bring down the enemies by taunting the opposing front line.
所以蹦跶着过去，看看能不能把他们惹毛
So skip your way on up there and maybe see if you can piss them off real good.
我脑子进水了才想会干那种事吧？
Why on earth would I want to do that?
当然，斥责士兵是个让你小命不保的好方法
Sure, chastising soldiers can be a great life hack for getting your life hacked,
但它也能奇迹般地打乱敌方阵型
but it can also work wonders for breaking enemy formations.
就拿征服者威廉的小丑泰耶费尔来说
Take Taillefer, a jester for William the Conqueror.
传说在一次战斗前，他骑马冲向英格兰敌军
Legend says that before one battle, he rode out towards the enemy English troops,
一边唱歌一边耍剑，还杀了一个冲出来跟他单挑的英国佬
sang while juggling his sword, and killed an Englishman who ran out to fight him.
然后他英勇地冲向敌阵，在倒下前又干掉了四个
He then valiantly charged the enemy line, where he killed four more before falling.
尽管他英年早逝，诺曼人最终还是赢得了那场战斗
But despite his untimely demise, the Normans would go on to win the battle.
呃，需要泰耶费尔的时候他人呢？
Uh, where's Taillefer when you need him?
哦，那场战斗就是这场
Oh, that battle was this one.
他就在那儿，带着英格兰人的杀气向你冲过来了
He's right there, charging towards you with English bloodlust.
我要用你的内脏玩杂耍，用你的牙当我鲁特琴的拨片！
I'm going to juggle your organs and pluck me loot with your tooth!
啊！我该怎么办？
Gah! What do I do?
我哪知道，用你的小丑训练打败他呗
I don't know, defeat him with your jester training or something.
我根本不知道怎么当小丑！
I don't know how to be a jester!
也是，也许我们该从基础开始
Yeah, maybe we should start with the basics first.
好吧，这个我们待会儿再说
Alright, we'll come back to this later.
我们为啥在船上？
Why are we on a ship?
我说了要教你基础知识
I said I was gonna teach you the basics.
小丑在船上学得最好吗？
And jesters learn best on ships?
啥？
What?
不，是海军基础
No, semen basics.
也就是新兵训练营
As in boot camp.
你要加入海军了
You're joining the Navy.
为啥？
Why?
广告时间，请空降6:36
当然是为了学《战舰世界》的战术啊
Why, to learn tactics for World of Warships, of course.
在你学习王室宫廷的门道之前，我们得先让你进去
Before you learn the ins and outs of the royal court, we gotta get you there in the first place.
对你来说幸运的是，对小丑的需求几乎是一个普遍常数
Luckily for you, the need for gesturing was practically a universal constant,
几乎每个主要文明都在某个时期流行过他们
with almost every major civilization having them in vogue at one point or another.
英国人当然有他们的傻瓜
The English, of course, had their fools.
罗马人有他们的丑角
The Romans, their Balatros.
牛仔队有他们的粉丝
The Cowboys, their fans.
几乎你能想到的每一种文化，都有他们可以嘲笑的傻瓜
Practically every culture you can think of had their share of stupid people to laugh at.
虽然要概括这么多文化中成为小丑的各种途径是不可能的
And while it's impossible to generalize the various routes to jesterdom across so many cultures,
但我们还是要这么做
we're gonna do it anyway
并将其归纳为三条异想天开的道路，让你戴上那顶王室帽子和铃铛
and narrow it down to three whimsical paths to snag in your royal cap and bells.
假设你选择成为一个后天小丑
Let's say you choose to be an artificial jester,
也就是一个通过辛勤努力来完善自己技艺的人
or a person that puts in good old-fashioned elbow grease to perfect their craft.
他们是杂耍家、喜剧演员，还有翻滚的杂技演员，掌握着各种技能
These were your jugglers, humblers, and acrobatic tumblers, employing a wide variety of skills,
从唱歌、诗歌到魔术和讲笑话
from singing and poetry to magic and jokery.
但训练你的智慧和才能只是小菜一碟
But training your wit and talent is the easy part,
事情开始变得棘手的地方，是如何获得“宫廷小丑”头衔中的“宫廷”二字
where things start to get dicey as acquiring that court part of the court jester title.
好吧，那我我去参加个试镜之类的就行了
Okay, so I'll just go audition or something.
事情不是那么运作的，Alex
Not quite how it works, Alex.
大多数情况下，招募宫廷小丑的过程非常不正式
For the most part, recruiting court jesters was a stupendously informal process,
跟好莱坞电影选角差不多
quite similar to that of casting Hollywood movies.
电影的主角不会给最有才华、试镜表现最好的女演员
A film's lead role doesn't go to the most talented actress with the best audition,
而是给哈维·韦恩斯坦最喜欢的那位
it goes to Harvey Weinstein's favorite.
同样地，一个欧洲宫廷小丑可以有各种各样不正式的出身
In a much similar vein, a European court jester can have a wide number of informal origins.
他们可能是不愿循规蹈矩的大学辍学生
They could be a college dropout who refused to conform,
也可能是个爱讲笑话的当地铁匠
or a local blacksmith who jokes up a storm,
一个因为跟修女调情被赶出来的修士
a thrown-out monk who flirted with nuns,
或者一个最擅长双关语的杂耍家
or a jungler most skilled with puns.
无论工作、特权或阶级如何
Regardless of job, privilege, or class,
你只需要通过一个测试
there'd be only one test you are to pass.
当你看到一个贵族时，逗他笑，然后就能得到一顶帽子
When you see an aristocrat, make him laugh and get a hat.
啥，就这样？
What, that's it?
差不多吧
Pretty much, yeah.
别忘了我们说的是在像《间谍亚契》和《救援高手》这种剧出现之前的时代
Keep in mind we're talking about a time before stuff like Archer and Nathan Fielder existed.
高质量的喜剧相当稀缺
Quality comedy was in rather short supply.
最标志性的英国小丑之一是一个叫“放屁罗兰”的人
One of the most iconic English jesters was a man by the name of Roland the Farter.
你大胆猜猜他的招牌绝活是啥
Take a wild guess what his signature act was.
嗯，放屁？
Um, farting.
呃，Alex，我们谈论的可是英国王室
Uh, Alex, this is the English crown we're talking about.
他们可比那有品位多了
They're more sophisticated than that.
花式跳跃、吹口哨和放屁，三样同时进行
It was a simultaneous jump, whistle, and fart
每年圣诞节都要表演，赢得理查国王的掌声和耶稣的眼泪
performed every Christmas to the applause of King Richard in the Tears of Jesus.
那个时代的喜剧门槛相当低
The bar for comedy was pretty low in these times.
好了，我们有两根蜡烛，一打鸡蛋，呃……
Okay, so we have two candles, a dozen eggs, uh...
这些洋葱上面没有价格
These onions don't have a price on them.
哦，那它们肯定是免费的
Huh, well then, they must be free.
我打赌他把它们放后备箱了
I bet he put them in the trunk!
需要注意的是，不同地区对小丑会有不同的偏好特质
It's important to note that different regions will have different desirable traits in the jester.
所以在谋求宫廷职位之前，一定要做足功课
So make sure you do your homework before pursuing a court position.
例如，像俄罗斯这样的地方，你可能更难被选中
For example, you might have a harder time being chosen in a place like Russia.
根据比阿特丽斯·奥托的说法
Where, according to Beatrice Otto,
那里的小丑通常是从年老和丑陋的农民中挑选出来的
the jesters were typically chosen from the older and uglier peasants.
而且他们越老，对他们的有趣期望值越高
And the older they were, the funnier they were expected to be.
这个怎么样
What about this one?
我看不懂
I don't understand.
他是怕碰球吗？
Is he afraid to touch balls?
嗯，我们知道你可不怕
Well, we know you aren't.
Alex，别在公共场合说这个
Alec, not in public.
天哪，你还活着吗
Jesus, are you alive?
哦，活不久了
Oh, not for long.
我有结肠癌四期
I have stage four colon cancer.
这太特么搞笑了
That is fucking hilarious.
虽然被选入王室宫廷需要很大的运气，要在对的时间出现在对的地点
While being picked for the royal court involved a lot of luck being in the right place at the right time,
但你也可以采取一些措施来增加几率
there were measures you could take to nudge the odds in your favor.
为了提高你的曝光度，你可以加入一个傻瓜协会
To boost your visibility, you could join a fool society.
可以理解为一群四处巡演的街头艺人，接活儿在各种场合上耍杂技、玩抛接
Your typical group of traveling entertainers who were hired for events to perform acrobatics and juggling.
或者你也可以施展你的音乐才华，成为一名吟游诗人
Or perhaps you could stretch your musical muscles and become a minstrel.
这些人通过表演来娱乐大众
People who put on shows for the amusement of the public.
对全家人来说都是很好的娱乐
All around good fun for the whole family.
只要你别把这两个词放在一起
So long as you don't put the two words together.
黑脸滑稽戏（Minstrel show），一般由白人演员涂黑面部饰演黑人，有种族歧视之意味
即使有了这些课程
Even with these lessons,
这一切对于成为一名宫廷小丑来说，似乎仍然是一个相当大的障碍啊
this all still seems like a pretty large hurdle to becoming a court jester.
是成为一名“后天”宫廷小丑，Alex
To becoming an artificial court jester, Alec.
这个名字暗示了还有另一种，并且在许多文化中更受欢迎的傻瓜类型
Such a name implies there is another, and in many cultures a more desirable type of fool,
“天生”小丑
the natural jester.
顾名思义，天生小丑就是一个在傻瓜艺术方面天赋异禀的人
Just like it sounds, a natural jester was a person so intrinsically gifted in the art of foolery,
仿佛他们生来就是干这个的
it was as if they were born to be one.
一个仅仅出现在王室宫廷，就能让大厅充满欢声笑语和喜悦的小丑
A jester whose mere presence in a royal court was all that was needed to flood the halls with laughter, joy, and mirth.
哇哦，所以就像罗宾·威廉姆斯？一个非常有魅力又搞笑的人
Wow, so like Robin Williams? Just a very charismatic and funny person?
不，拜托，Alex，你知道这是个什么样的频道
No, come on, Alex. You know what kind of channel this is.
这些孩子实际上有严重的残疾，这让他们成为富裕家庭的抢手货
The kids were actually severely disabled, making them ripe for the picking by wealthy families
他们可以花少至20荷兰盾就从牧鹅人那里买下他们
who could cop them from goose herds for as little as 20 guilders.
虽然买一个残疾孩子来取笑听起来很操蛋
While it sounds pretty fucked up to purchase a disabled kid to laugh at,
但总的来说，很少有证据表明这样做不是出于慈善目的
in general, there's very little to suggest this wasn't done to be charitable.
毕竟，当小克劳斯不停地用皮带勒死鹅时，要完成你的牧鹅定额是相当困难的
After all, it's rather difficult to meet your goose quota when little Claus keeps strangling them under his belt,
而且在富裕贵族的照顾下长大，很难说是一种艰难的生活
and growing up in the care of wealthy nobles could hardly be called a difficult life.
如果你是英格兰的天生小丑就要小心了
Just be careful if you're a natural in England,
因为有很多案例显示他们是因为邪恶的原因被招募来的
as there were numerous cases of them being recruited for nefarious reasons.
当时有一种叫做“乞求傻子”的恶行：监护人会恶意操纵法庭
In a practice called begging a fool, caregivers would abuse the courts
将受害者合法地变为“疯子”，进而榨取他们的财产
to get victims legally declared insane to profit off them,
因为法律允许将“白痴”（他们原话）的资产
as laws allowed the assets of an idiot, their words,
转移给照顾他们的人
to be transferred to whoever was taking care of them.
什么？太可怕了
What? That's terrible.
我不敢相信这种事曾经存在过
I can't believe that used to exist.
用过去式的时候小心点，Alex
Careful with the past tense there, Alex.
操纵傻瓜牟利的做法如今依然存在
The practice of manipulating idiots for profit is actually alive and well today.
只是现在的说法变成了“订阅OnlyFans”
It's just that the term has since changed to subscribing to OnlyFans.
总之，你要是想走“天生小丑”这条路
But anyway, if you want to pursue the natural jester route,
那显然得满足几个基本条件
obviously you're going to have to meet a few prerequisites.
所以我们先让你残疾一下
So let's go ahead and disable you a bit.
嘿，等等！
Hey, wait!
这……这有效果吗？我没感觉有什么不同
D-did that do anything? I don't feel different.
呵。你……你在暗示什么
Huh. W-what are you insinuating?
和他们的后天同行一样
As with their artificial counterparts,
天生小丑也常常像从糖果机里取糖球一样，直接从街上被挑走
naturals too, were often just plucked off the streets like gumballs from a machine.
也就是说这事儿取决于有没有路过的朝臣一时兴起，正好想找个小丑来取乐
That is, so long as a passing courtier happens to find themselves with a sweet tooth.
我告诉过你国王不会喜欢上一个的
I told you the king wouldn't like the last one.
我哪知道那家伙就会一个笑话啊？
Well, how was I to know the man was a one joke wonder?
你也听到了吧，贝蒂
You heard him, Betty.
没标价就肯定是免费的，这太有才了
With no price tag, it must be free. That's genius.
哎呀得了吧
Oh, please.
如果我想整天听男人笑得跟快淹死了一样
If I wanted to spend my days listening to men choke that hard,
我早就去当救生员了
I'd be a lifeguard.
那么这个怎么样
Now, what about this one?
不，国王明确表示他想要一个天生的
No, the king specified he wanted a natural.
嘿伙计们，你们看《生活大爆炸》最新一集了吗
Hey guys, you seen the new episode of the Big Bang Theory?
亲爱的，我们挖到宝了
Honey, we've struck gold.
不过，“天生”并不仅仅指有精神缺陷的人
Naturals didn't just mean people with mental deformities, however.
也包括身体上的缺陷
It also included the physical as well.
从阿兹特克到中国，侏儒都是王室宫廷的标配
Dwarves were a staple of royal courts from the Aztecs to China,
有些文化甚至最珍视他们，重视程度远超其他小丑
with some cultures cherishing them most of all jesters.
奥斯曼帝国尤其喜爱他们的侏儒
The Ottoman Empire in particular loved their dwarves,
根据一本法国旅行日志记载
and according to one French travelogue,
当发现一个侏儒同时又是哑巴、聋子和阉人时
when a dwarf is found who is also mute, deaf, and a eunuch,
他将被视为所有生物中最完美的存在
he is seen as the most perfect of all creatures,
比最英俊的男人更受钦佩
more admired than the most handsome man.
因此，在土耳其，你收集的残疾越多——就跟收集拉布布似的
So, when in Turkey, the more disabilities you collect like labubus,
你在苏丹眼中就越受宠
the more favored you'll be in the eyes of the sultan.
你可能不喜欢
You may not like it,
但这就是巅峰男性体格的样子
but this is what peak male physique looks like.
好吧，但为什么人们倾向于喜欢天生小丑而不是后天小丑呢？
Okay, but why did people tend to prefer natural jesters over artificial ones?
这真是个好问题，Alex
Now that is a fantastic question, Alex.
先抛开人类嘲笑异类的黑历史，几乎和侃爷的脸皮一样厚这个事实不谈
Other than the fact that humanity's history of laughing at different looking people is about as dense as Kanye West,
关于他们为何如此受欢迎，其实还有别的说法
there were other theories as to why they were so popular.
李·西格尔博士的理论认为，身体上的缺陷
Dr. Lee Siegel theorizes that corporeal disfiguration
是一种喜剧性的隐喻，它象征着精神的畸形
provides the comic metaphor for spiritual deformity,
智识的失衡、心理的固化以及情感的笨拙
intellectual disproportion, psychological rigidity, or emotional awkwardness.
简而言之，身边留一个畸形的人可以帮助国王时刻提醒自己
In short, keeping a deformed person around could help make sure a king doesn't forget that
他们也并非完美
they're not perfect themselves.
嘿国王，我是来应聘小丑的
Hey King, I'm here for the adjuster roll.
啊，这次他们派了谁来……
Ah, who did they send this time?
我的天哪
Oh my god.
我应该多和我妈妈聊聊
I should talk to my mother more often.
呃，什……什么
Uh, p-pardon.
是的，我本该赦免蒂莫西的
Yes, I should have pardoned Timothy.
就算我们那段不堪的关系曝光了又怎样呢？
Who cares if our scandalous relationship got out?
他曾是我的缪斯！
He was my muse.
哇哦，嘿，那我就玩会儿杂耍吧
Whoa, hey, so I'm just gonna juggle.
呵，我周旋于众男人之间，他们不过是我鲜嫩多汁的乐子罢了
Ah, the men I juggle like succulent toys of pleasure.
无论你选择天生小丑还是后天小丑的路线，每条路都有其相对的优缺点
Whether you go the natural or artificial jester route, each path will have the relative pros and cons.
但我们还没提到如果你是个女人，这会是什么样子
But we haven't even mentioned what this would all be like if you were a woman.
哦天哪
Oh god.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
肯定很糟糕吧
It must have been terrible.
还真不是
Actually, no.
小丑是历史上少数几个完全没有禁忌让女性担任的角色之一
Jestery was one of the few roles in history that was completely untaboo for women to take on,
她们享有与男性同行相同的尊重和责任，没有任何污名
sharing the same respect and responsibilities as their male counterparts without any stigma.
哈
Huh.
是啊
Yeah.
说实话，我本来以为会更糟
Not gonna lie, I expected worse.
这个频道上也不是所有事都那么糟糕，Alex
Not everything is terrible on this channel, Alex.
有时候历史也可以很酷
Sometimes history can be based.
哦
Oh.
嗯，那……那挺好的
Well, that-that's nice.
是啊
Yeah.
现在我们来聊聊儿童身体残害
Now let's talk about child bodily disfiguration.
呃
Uh.
任何人和他们的老妈都可以走后天小丑路线，但通常更受欢迎的天生小丑
Anyone and their mothers could pursue an artificial jester route, but the oft more desirable naturals
只能是天生的，不能后天制造
could only be born, not made.
对吧
Right?
隆重介绍“人造天生傻瓜”，也就是人工伪装成残疾的小丑
Introducing the artificial natural fool, or someone who artificially passes themselves off as a disabled jester.
这可以通过两种方式实现
Now, this could be done one of two ways.
你要么在余生中公开上演一出假装智障的顶级智斗
You could put on a class A act of feigning a mental deficiency in public for the rest of your days,
要么走那条更……有说服力的路
or you could take the more... convincing path.
这是一个小孩
This here is a child.
小孩非常柔软
A child is very squishy,
简直就是最棒的橡皮泥
making them excellent play-doh
父母有什么“艺术灵感”，都能在他们身上随心所欲地捏塑
for whatever work of art their parents find themselves inspired to make.
头顶有软囟？
Soft spot on head?
捏之！
Squeeze it.
年轻光滑的皮肤？
Young smooth skin?
烫之！
Burn it.
灵活的脚骨？
Flexible foot bones?
打断之！
Break them.
如果你想把孩子卖给王室宫廷牟利，就人工残害他们的身体
And if you wanted to sell off kids to royal courts for a profit, artificially mutilate their bodies,
或阻碍他们的生长，制造出怪诞的身体特征，或人造侏儒
or stunt their growth to create grotesque physical characteristics, or manufactured dwarves.
那……不可能是真的
That... can't be real.
你很可能说对了
And you very well might be right.
这一段的大部分信息都应该持怀疑态度
Much of the information in this section should be taken with a healthy sprinkle of doubt,
因为虽然存在关于这些做法的历史文献，但证据相当稀少
as while historical documents exist for these practices, evidence is sufficiently scarce that
大部分可能只是民间传说
much of it could just be chalked up to folklore.
那么让我们从最可能是虚构的故事开始
So let's start with the most likely fictitious tales
然后逐步转向那些毫无疑问是真实的事情
and work our way towards what was undoubtedly real.
如果你有幸出生在17世纪西班牙的一个贫困家庭
If you were lucky enough to be born to a poor family in 17th century Spain,
你可能会发现自己被卖给了Comprachicos
you could find yourself being pawned off to the Comprachicos.
Comprachicos是源于西班牙语的复合词，意为“儿童贩子”
想知道那是什么意思？
Wonder what that means.
民间传说称，这些团伙会通过身体束缚来阻碍孩子的生长
The folklore goes that the gangs would stunt a child's growth through either physical restraint,
束缚面部、割开眼睛、脱臼关节，手段无所不用其极
muzzling the face, slitting the eyes, dislocating joints, the works.
或者用蝙蝠、鼹鼠和睡鼠的油脂涂抹婴儿的脊椎
Or it could be done with anointing baby spines with the grease of bats, moles, and door mice,
又或是使用像矮接骨木、节草或雏菊汁这样的药物
and with drugs like dwarf elder, knot grass, or daisy juice.
这些名字听起来像是有人对着字典乱扔飞镖起的
All things that sound like someone just threw darts at a dictionary.
在残疾人工厂待上一段时间后，据说他们会被作为小丑和宫廷侏儒出售牟利
After some time in the cripple factory, they'd supposedly be sold off for a profit as jesters and court dwarfs
以满足日益增长的需求
to meet the growing demand.
Comprachicos这个词是维克多·雨果在他的一本书中创造的
The term Comprachicos was coined by Victor Hugo in one of his books,
他坚称这些团伙在历史上真实存在
a man who attests to the historical existence of these gangs.
不过虽然我的一些资料来源怀疑其确切存在
While some of my sources doubt that exact existence,
但有些声称类似的做法在历史上不同时期确实发生过
some claim similar practices did take place in different times throughout history.
比阿特丽斯·奥托也指出，这种做法甚至为莎士比亚所知
Beatrice Otto also points out that the practice was even known to Shakespeare,
他在《仲夏夜之梦》中提到了“侏儒制造鸡尾酒”
who references the Dwarfenator cocktail in A Midsummer Night's Dream.
但如果你出生在贫困的墨西哥家庭
But what if you were born to an impoverished Mexico family,
生活在16世纪之交的阿兹特克首都呢
living in the Aztec capital at the turn of the 16th century?
嗯，如果爸爸妈妈碰巧心情不错，想搞点小创作
Well, if mom and pop were in a rather crafty mood,
他们也可以阻碍你的生长，希望改善你的人生机会
they too could stunt your growth in hopes of improving your chances at life.
侏儒和驼背者在蒙特祖马二世的随从中非常受欢迎
Dwarves and hunchbacks were very popular additions to Montezuma II's retinue,
以至于他们甚至有自己的专属住所
so much so that they even had their own special quarters,
配备持续的医疗监督
complete with constant medical supervision,
还有为其他男人、女人、豹猫、熊准备的房间……
along with rooms for other men, women, ocelots, bears...
什么，像动物园吗？
What, like a zoo?
这可是你说的，Alex
Your words, Alex.
当然，说句公道话，我们现在也搞不清楚这个“皇家动物园人类部”
Although, to be fair, it's unclear if the human portion of the Royal Zoo
到底是什么情况。是真把人关笼子里，让游客扔花生逗着玩？
was truly people in cages to throw peanuts at,
or if they were just merely private rooms in the same facility,
还是说，他们只是住在同一个地方，但有自己的单间？
or in a different building altogether.
又或者，他们住的楼跟动物园压根就不是一回事？
阿兹特克的历史是出了名的自相矛盾
Aztec history is famously contradictory.
但无论如何，侏儒被视为雨神的孩子
But regardless, Dwarves were seen as children of the Rain God,
他们可以担任小丑和皇帝信任的仆人
who could act as jesters and trusted servants to the Emperor.
所以，如果你得到了这份工作
So, if you land yourself in this occupation,
一定要全心全意地投入
really make sure you put your heart into it.
因为作为侏儒，你与神有联系
Because with your divine connection as a dwarf,
你的心是第一个被取走的
yours is first in line to be taken.
当然，身体畸形只是天生小丑硬币的一面
Of course, physical deformities were only one side of the natural coin.
在像15世纪的苏格兰这样的地方
In places like 15th century Scotland,
装傻以试图获得天生小丑的工作
the practice of feigning a folly to try and snag a natural gig
成了一项相当有利可图的生意
became such a profitable hustle,
以至于不得不通过一项法律来制止它
that a law had to be passed to put a stop to it.
如果你被当场抓到假装智力残疾
If you were caught red-handed pretending to be mentally disabled,
他们肯定会让你变成身体残疾
they'd be sure to make you physically disabled,
惩罚包括钉耳朵和截肢
with punishments like ear nailing and amputation.
这样到头来，你会成为一个真正的天生小丑
So, at the end of the day, you would become a genuine natural.
不过只是一个可能不会玩杂耍的小丑
Just one that might not be able to juggle.
当然，我想，一个人也可以假装有身体残疾
Surely, I imagine, one could also pretend to have a physical disability
来让自己更引人注目
to make them stand out more.
尤其是如果他们已经有一个残疾可以配合的话
Especially if they already had one to accompany it.
但我认为这样的把戏会更难成功
But I think such a stunt would be a bit harder to pull off.
那么，你出价多少？
So, what are you offering?
用我这个聋子天生侏儒换你那个后天放屁人怎么样？
How about my deaf natural dwarf for your artificial whistle-farter?
评级了吗？
Is it graded?
九九成，稀罕物
Mid-nine condition.
太好了
Excellent.
不能让别人听到我痔疮的事
Can't have anyone else hearing about my hemorrhoids.
呃，那byd刚才是听见我说话了吗？
Um, did that thing just fucking hear me?
既然我们已经讲完了成为小丑的三条路
Now that we've covered the three routes to jesterdom,
我们得弄清楚你在新王室家中的职责是什么
we gotta figure out what your responsibilities will be in your new royal home.
你的基本职责当然是既要当个艺人又要当个值得信赖的顾问
Your basics, of course, will be serving as both an entertainer and a trusted advisor,
用俏皮话、翻跟头和魔术来取悦宫廷的赞助人
using quips, flips, and magic tricks to amuse the patrons of the court,
同时劝说你的国王不要随便杀害平民
while talking down your king from killing random peasants.
嗯，什么？
Huh, what?
哦看，你的国王来了
Oh look, here's your king now.
也许你可以试试让那张尊贵的脸上露出笑容
Maybe see if you can plop a smile on that regal mug.
嗯，所以，嘿，那个，为什么，呃，小鸡要过马路？
Um, so, hey, like, why did the, uh, chicken cross the road?
我不知道，也许我会在我杀了你之后跟他喝杯啤酒问问！
I don't know, maybe I'll ask him over a beer right after I FUCKING KILL YOU!
嘎
Gah!
虽然小丑被他们的王室主子直接杀掉的情况不常见
While it wasn't common for jesters to be outright killed by their royal patrons,
但这并不意味着他们一直不会受到威胁
that doesn't mean they weren't threatened, like, all the time.
作为一个傻瓜，你通常拥有无与伦比的特权，可以随心所欲地说任何话
As a fool, you generally have an unparalleled privilege to say whatever you please,
几乎是王室宫廷中唯一能够向权力说真话的成员
being practically the only member of a royal court that was able to speak truth to power.
但即使有人期望你拿统治者开玩笑
But even though you were expected to make jokes at a ruler's expense,
这并不意味着他们归根结底不是小气又有钱的混蛋
that doesn't mean they weren't still, at the end of the day, petty rich assholes.
后唐伶人敬新磨有一次开玩笑说
The Chinese jester, Jingxin Mo, was once chased by a dog when he cracked a joke
敬新磨（?—?），五代十国人物，后唐的宫廷艺人，一作镜新磨
皇帝不该让他的孩子到处咬人，结果被狗追
that the emperor shouldn't let his kids run around biting people.
欧阳修《新五代史·伶官传》载：
新磨尝奏事殿中，殿中多恶犬，新磨去，一犬起逐之
新磨倚柱而呼曰：“陛下毋纵儿女啮人！”庄宗家世夷狄，夷狄之人讳狗，故新磨以此讥之
庄宗大怒，弯弓注矢将射之，新磨急呼曰：“陛下无杀臣！臣与陛下为一体，杀之不祥！”
庄宗大惊，问其故，对曰：“陛下开国，改元同光，天下皆谓陛下同光帝
且同，铜也，若杀敬新磨，则同无光矣。”
庄宗大笑，乃释之
皇帝被惹恼了，用弓箭瞄准他
Taking offense, the emperor aimed his bow at him,
只是因为这个傻瓜的第二个笑话碰巧说中了，才收回了箭
and only stayed his arrow after the fool's second joke happened to land.
无论是处决、放逐，甚至是截肢
Whether it be execution, banishment, or even amputation,
历史上都有大量小丑依靠智慧
there are a plethora of anecdotes throughout history of jesters relying on wit
逃避惩罚的轶事，仿佛他们的生命就悬于此
to evade punishments as if their life depended on it.
因为事实就是如此
Because it did.
但你的俏皮话并非总是围绕着避免处决
But your witticisms won't always revolve around avoiding executions.
它们也可以用来增强处决的效果
They could also serve to enhance them.
例如，伊凡雷帝的俄罗斯小丑
The Russian jesters for Ivan the Terrible, for instance,
就被要求在处决前后逗沙皇发笑
were tasked with making the Tsar laugh before and after an execution.
这家伙自己也挺傻的，不是吗？
This guy's kind of fooled himself, isn't he?
嗯，现在不是了
Well, not anymore.
有了直言不讳的执照
Having a license, to be brutally honest,
你也会被派去向王室传达坏消息
you'll also be tasked with delivering bad news to royalty.
所以，作为一名宫廷小丑，你需要巧妙地用双关语
So, as a court jester, you're gonna need to juggle, pun intended,
在准确告知国王可怕事件的同时
accurately informing your king about a terrible event,
撒上足够的幽默来让他冷静并保住你的脑袋
while sprinkling in just enough humor to calm his head and keep yours.
在斯勒伊斯海战中，英国人击溃了法国舰队后
After the English routed the French ships in the Battle of Sloys,
向法王菲利普六世陛下通报
it was up to the jester of France's King Philip VI,
他海军惨败的任务就落在了他的宫廷小丑身上
to inform his majesty of his navy's terrible defeat.
为此，他走到国王面前大喊
To do so, he went to the king and shouted,
“英国懦夫！胆小的英国人”
THE ENGLISH COWARDS! THE LILLY LIVERED ENGLISH!
这种情绪我们通常都感同身受
A sentiment that, of course, we all normally share,
但国王还是让他做一下笑点解析
but the king asked for an explanation anyway,
他回答说
to which he said,
“他们甚至没有勇气像我们勇敢的法国人一样跳进水里！”
THEY DON'T EVEN HAVE THE GUTS TO JUMP INTO THE WATER LIKE OUR BRAVE FRENCH!
哈
Huh.
什么？
What?
我只是以为你会说个“法国人真差劲”的笑话
I guess I was just expecting a French people bad joke from you.
我不能啊，Alex
I can't, Alex!
你玩过《33号远征队》吗
Have you played Expedition 33?
那游戏太棒了！
That game's incredible!
恐怕法国人现在变潮酷了
I'm afraid the French are based now.
但是嘿，你可以尽情地拿他们开玩笑
But hey, you've got free reign to joke about them as much as you want.
我为什么要那么做？
Why would I want to do that?
大概是因为你要告诉国王他老婆跟一个法国外交官有一腿吧
Probably because you're gonna tell the king about his wife cheating on him with a French diplomat.
啥？
What?
祝你好运喵
Good luck!
嘿
Hey.
哈哈哈
Ha ha ha!
呃，所以，呃，你知道什么存放法棍的好方法吗？
Uh, so, uh, know any good ways to store a baguette?
嗯，你老婆肯定知道
Well, your wife sure does.
啊！
Ah!
你不仅仅是向你的王室主子传递信息
You won't just be delivering information to your royal patron.
被托付了高度敏感信息后，这意味着你可能还需要奔波于异国他乡传递消息
Being trusted with highly sensitive information means you could also find yourself running messages all across foreign lands.
其中也包括战场
Which also included the battlefield.
也包括敌方阵营
Which also included the enemy camp.
投降条件是吧？
Terms of surrender, huh?
好的，很好
Okay, great.
请……到我办公室来一下
Just, uh, step into my office.
作为一个有幽默感的可靠顾问
Being a trusted advisor with a sense of humor,
你在微妙的外交任务中也会是个非常有用的资产
you'll also be quite the useful asset for delicate diplomatic missions.
偶尔也包括打架
And occasionally fist fights.
呃，不好意思
Uh, I'm sorry.
在谈判桌上有一个直言不讳的傻瓜对于缓解紧张局势至关重要
Having a blunt full at the negotiating table could prove vital for easing tensions.
这正是匈牙利国王马蒂亚斯和波希米亚国王乔治
Which was precisely the hopes of Kings Matias of Hungary and George of Bohemia
在一场战斗后在帐篷里会面谈判时所希望的
when they met in a tent for negotiations after a battle.
在一次用餐时
During a meal,
一位贵族觉得如果让每个国王的小丑通过打一架来决定
a noble thought it'd be funny if each king's gesture were to decide
天主教和胡斯派新教谁优谁劣会很有趣
between Catholicism and Hussite Protestantism by having a fist fight.
因为当宗教和暴力搅和在一起时，从来不会出什么好事
Because nothing ever bad happens when both religion and violence are involved.
国王们同意了，只要他们以骑士的方式战斗
The kings gave them the thumbs up, so long as they fought in a knightly manner.
但这并没有持续多久，因为当匈牙利小丑开始落于下风时
Which didn't last too long, as when he started to lose,
他拿起了一个
the Hungarian jester picked up, quote,
“骇人的机器”并扔向了波希米亚小丑
the monstrous machine and chucked it at the Bohemian.
我完全不知道是什么样的地球设备能让一个历史学家觉得
I have no idea what earthly device could prompt a historian
唯一可能的描述方式就是称它为“骇人的”
to think that the only possible way to describe it would be to call it monstrous,
所以我只能得出结论，要么是匈牙利小丑有一个恶魔般的赞助人
so I can only conclude either the Hungarian had a fiendish patron
让他能够接触到来自物质位面之外的恶魔装置
who granted him access to demonic contraptions from beyond this material plane,
要么他只是扔了个假牛至之类的东西
or he just threw a dildo or something.
不管怎样，据说这引起了一场骚乱，看起来就要变成一场血战，直到国王介入
Either way, it's said this caused an uproar that began to look like a bloodbath until the king stepped in.
人类从此吸取了关于宗教冲突的教训
And humanity forever learned their lesson about religious conflict.
鉴于小丑与国王的关系如此密切，你必须在困难时期陪伴在他身边
With how close a jester was to his king, you'll have to stick by his side during times of hardship.
例如，侏儒小丑玛图琳
For example, the dwarf jester Mathurine
曾冒着生命危险困住了一个企图刺杀她的国王亨利四世但未遂的刺客
risked her life trapping an assassin who failed to kill her king, Henry IV.
在另一个故事中
In another story,
当神圣罗马帝国皇帝马克西米利安一世被囚禁时
when the Holy Roman Emperor Maximilian I was imprisoned,
他的小丑闯入并请求代替他受过
his jester broke in and pleaded to take his place.
所以一定要练习握紧肥皂，因为作为一名小丑，国王可能会期望你代他受罚
So make sure you practice keeping a grip on the soap, because as a jester you may be expected to take your king's punishment in their stead.
法庭认定你犯有对人民的叛国罪
The tribune finds you guilty of high treason to your people,
为此你被判处鞭笞、剥皮、三度烧伤、一度烧伤
for which you are hereby sentenced to flogging, flaying, third-degree burning, first-degree burning,
每三根手指断头、烙印、挖眼、二度烧伤和鼠刑
guillotining of every third finger, branding, eye gouging, second-degree burning, and death by rats.
被告还有什么问题吗？
Does the defendant have any questions?
你觉得这样还能接受吗
So is that, like, good with you?
如果你发现自己是爱尔兰的小丑，我希望你充满爱国情怀
And if you found yourself as a jester in Ireland, I hope you're feeling patriotic,
因为无私的行为是爱尔兰小丑的标志
because selfless acts were rather iconic of Irish jesters.
故事讲述了爱尔兰的傻瓜在战斗中代替他们的主人赴死
Stories tell of Irish fools replacing their masters in battle to die in their stead,
或甚至选择与他们一同死去，以便在天堂相伴
or even choosing to die by their side to join them in heaven.
哇哦
Whoa!
天哪，幸好没打中我们
Holy, glad that missed us.
是啊，看起来我刚刚打中了那边那个爱尔兰国王
Yeah, looks like I just hit that Irish king over there.
呃，Alex，我的孩子，啊，看来我们到头了
Ugh, Alex, me boy, ah, it seems as be the end for us.
呃，我们
Uh, us.
来吧，小伙子，与我一同拥抱死亡
Come, laddie, join us in death's embrace.
我其实完全没事
I'm actually completely fine.
不，我们必须一起死，我的兄弟
No, we must die together, my brother.
我命令你
I order you.
BlueJay，救我
BlueJay, help me.
Alex，拜托了
Alex, please.
我怎么能拒绝一个国王最后的愿望呢
Who am I to deny a king his final wish?
求你了
Please!
如果我死了你就不能折磨我了
You can't torture me if I'm dead!
你可真了解我
You know me so well.
说到底，小丑最重要的任务是使他们的统治者人性化
At the end of the day, the most important task a jester has is to humanize their ruler.
凭借你对宫廷成员情绪和习惯的独特洞察力
With your unique insight into the moods and tics of the members of court,
以及你诚实、新奇和整体喜剧的执照
and with your license of honesty, novelty, and overall comedy,
你，且只有你，将与你的国王建立最深厚、最深刻的联系
you and you alone will have the deepest, most profound connection with your king.
伴随这种影响力而来的是巨大的责任
With this influence comes great responsibility,
因为不受约束的权力会滋生一种致盲的腐朽
as unchecked power breeds a blinding rot,
这种腐朽如果不以同理心之光加以抵制，就会溃烂流血
a rot that festers and bleeds if not pushed back with the light of empathy.
而这束光，我亲爱的Alex，来自一个孤独的小丑，站在贪婪的黑暗虚空中
And this light, my dear Alex, shines from a lone jester, standing in the dark void of greed.
这个职位，尽管充满了愚蠢的轻浮，却是至关重要的
This position, for all its silly frivolity, is a vital one,
因为你与国王的紧密联系将是他人生活中无人能及的
as your close-knit bond with the king will be unrivaled by anyone else in his life.
那么，Alex，你能承担起这份责任吗？
So, Alex, can you take up this responsibility?
你能在宫廷小丑这个岗位上，活下来吗？
Can you survive, as a court jester?
我……我能！
I... I can.
我将做正确的事，为了所有人的利益
I will do what is right, for the good of all people.
太好了！看来我们可以继续我们的战斗了
Excellent! Looks like we can resume our battle then.
哈？
Huh?
你在这儿啊，你这个英国小娘炮
There you are, you English twink!
啊？
Gah!
啊，会没事的
Ah, it'll be just fine.
小丑的历史
The history of jesters.
10分满分给20星
20 out of 10 stars.